<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Mental Health on Lee Hatcher</title><link>https://leehatcher.com/categories/mental-health/</link><description>Recent content in Mental Health on Lee Hatcher</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://leehatcher.com/categories/mental-health/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Interdisciplinary Consultation or Collaboration in Gender Affirming Care</title><link>https://leehatcher.com/2022/10/interdisciplinary-consultation-or-collaboration-in-gender-affirming-care/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://leehatcher.com/2022/10/interdisciplinary-consultation-or-collaboration-in-gender-affirming-care/</guid><description>I will discuss the current practices of care for mental health professionals (MHP) working with transgender or gender nonconforming (TGNC) clients. These conventions suggest the best practice of care and the continuation of future TGNC care. The common thread of the articles helps to answer the question: How can mental health professionals provide affirmative care to their transgender clients in which they feel validated and supported within their practice? The three articles and book I have chosen to discuss are prevalent to me as a transgender person, and all have aided in informing me of the expectations and realities of working with TGNC clients.</description></item><item><title>Professional Identity Personal Essay: Gender in the Workplace</title><link>https://leehatcher.com/2022/09/professional-identity-personal-essay-gender-in-the-workplace/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://leehatcher.com/2022/09/professional-identity-personal-essay-gender-in-the-workplace/</guid><description>My life, admittedly, is not ‘normal’ like most others. I put quotations around normal because I understand that society dictates social normalities. Still, I reject the idea that there is one ideal that we as a society should all mold ourselves into. Therefore, I will acknowledge the term ‘normal’ only as a frame of reference. I am not ‘normal’ because I am a transgender, gay, autistic white male. These identities do not define who I am; they are who I am.</description></item><item><title>Gender Affirmation and Depressive Symptoms</title><link>https://leehatcher.com/2022/04/gender-affirmation-and-depressive-symptoms/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://leehatcher.com/2022/04/gender-affirmation-and-depressive-symptoms/</guid><description>The lifetime suicide rate for transgender youth is around 45%, roughly nine times the suicide rate of the U.S. population (Johns et al., 2019; James et al., 2016; Haas, Rodgers, &amp;amp; Herman, 2014). This is because transgender youth have higher rates of exposure to victimization, discrimination, and harassment which can lead to depressive symptoms (Austin et al., 2018; Bauer et al., 2015; Bockting et al., 2013; Johns et al., 2019). Depressive symptoms can include having a depressed mood, loss of interest in activities one once enjoyed, or thoughts of death or suicide (Torres, 2020).</description></item><item><title>Augusten Burroughs: Abnormal Psychology and Substance Abuse</title><link>https://leehatcher.com/2021/12/augusten-burroughs-abnormal-psychology-and-substance-abuse/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://leehatcher.com/2021/12/augusten-burroughs-abnormal-psychology-and-substance-abuse/</guid><description>Augusten Burroughs, aged 27, is a caucasian male whose first and only language is English. His current occupation is as a creative freelancer in the advertising business. He lives in an apartment in an affluent part of Manhattan, New York. Mr. Burrough’s presenting problem, as stated by coworkers, has been that ``[There are] many instances where [his] drinking has had an effect on [his] performance- I myself have smelled alcohol on [him] numerous times&amp;rsquo;' (Burroughs, 2003, p.</description></item></channel></rss>