<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Lee Hatcher</title><link>https://leehatcher.com/</link><description>Recent content on Lee Hatcher</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://leehatcher.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Interdisciplinary Consultation or Collaboration in Gender Affirming Care</title><link>https://leehatcher.com/2022/10/interdisciplinary-consultation-or-collaboration-in-gender-affirming-care/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://leehatcher.com/2022/10/interdisciplinary-consultation-or-collaboration-in-gender-affirming-care/</guid><description>I will discuss the current practices of care for mental health professionals (MHP) working with transgender or gender nonconforming (TGNC) clients. These conventions suggest the best practice of care and the continuation of future TGNC care. The common thread of the articles helps to answer the question: How can mental health professionals provide affirmative care to their transgender clients in which they feel validated and supported within their practice? The three articles and book I have chosen to discuss are prevalent to me as a transgender person, and all have aided in informing me of the expectations and realities of working with TGNC clients.</description></item><item><title>Professional Identity Personal Essay: Gender in the Workplace</title><link>https://leehatcher.com/2022/09/professional-identity-personal-essay-gender-in-the-workplace/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://leehatcher.com/2022/09/professional-identity-personal-essay-gender-in-the-workplace/</guid><description>My life, admittedly, is not ‘normal’ like most others. I put quotations around normal because I understand that society dictates social normalities. Still, I reject the idea that there is one ideal that we as a society should all mold ourselves into. Therefore, I will acknowledge the term ‘normal’ only as a frame of reference. I am not ‘normal’ because I am a transgender, gay, autistic white male. These identities do not define who I am; they are who I am.</description></item><item><title>Professional Identity Personal Essay: Gender in the Workplace</title><link>https://leehatcher.com/2022/09/professional-identity-personal-essay-gender-in-the-workplace/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://leehatcher.com/2022/09/professional-identity-personal-essay-gender-in-the-workplace/</guid><description>My life, admittedly, is not ‘normal’ like most others. I put quotations around normal because I understand that society dictates social normalities. Still, I reject the idea that there is one ideal that we as a society should all mold ourselves into. Therefore, I will acknowledge the term ‘normal’ only as a frame of reference. I am not ‘normal’ because I am a transgender, gay, autistic white male. These identities do not define who I am; they are who I am.</description></item><item><title>Examining Q.U.E.S.T.: A Doctoral Socialization Summer Research Program for BIPOC Student</title><link>https://leehatcher.com/2022/08/examining-q.u.e.s.t.-a-doctoral-socialization-summer-research-program-for-bipoc-student/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://leehatcher.com/2022/08/examining-q.u.e.s.t.-a-doctoral-socialization-summer-research-program-for-bipoc-student/</guid><description>Abstract Research shows the ability to transition from college to a graduate program requires scaffolding and support from the collegiate curriculum, faculty, and specialized programs. Currently, this transition is not being supported for BIPOC students in psychology programs based on a lack of the aforementioned. To better understand what impacts their transition, this proposal aims to investigate the program entitled “NYU’s Quality Undergraduate Education and Scholarly Training” (QUEST). QUEST is an Applied Psychology program that aims to mitigate negative transitional factors through mentorship and engagement in graduate research projects.</description></item><item><title>A Transgender Man: How My Development Through Adolescence Was Affected</title><link>https://leehatcher.com/2021/05/a-transgender-man-how-my-development-through-adolescence-was-affected/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://leehatcher.com/2021/05/a-transgender-man-how-my-development-through-adolescence-was-affected/</guid><description>Growing up, I faced a lot of adversity within what Bronfenbrenner would call the microsystem of my ecological system. I was raised in a white lower-middle-class family that encountered a heavy tragedy when I was only eight years old; because of this, my parents struggled with their own mental and emotional well-being, which in turn greatly impacted my life and still does to this day. There were other complexities in my life before then, such as my struggle with my gender identity, that played a large role in my becoming the person I am today.</description></item><item><title>Trans Women and Feminism: The Fight for Equality</title><link>https://leehatcher.com/2020/11/trans-women-and-feminism-the-fight-for-equality/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://leehatcher.com/2020/11/trans-women-and-feminism-the-fight-for-equality/</guid><description>In 2016, Ricky Gervais, actor, and comedian made a joke about Caitlyn Jenner while hosting the Golden Globes. She had recently gotten into trouble for having caused a fatal car crash, which was cause for Gervais’s joke claiming that she may have become a role model but “didn’t do alot for women drivers.&amp;quot; His entire monologue is tinged with sexist comments against the female audience, saying things such as “female [film] remakes are the big thing- and this is brilliant for the studios because they get guaranteed box office results and they don’t have to spend too much money on the cast!</description></item></channel></rss>