<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Psychology on Lee Hatcher</title><link>https://leehatcher.com/tags/psychology/</link><description>Recent content in Psychology on Lee Hatcher</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 04:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://leehatcher.com/tags/psychology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Invisible Identities</title><link>https://leehatcher.com/2022/10/invisible-identities/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://leehatcher.com/2022/10/invisible-identities/</guid><description>The Cultures of Psychology are vast; nuance and diversity are the spearheads of what it means to understand intersectionality and its role within a culture. Still, one continues to come to mind that has not necessarily had its chance on stage: Invisible Identities. I believe the idea of invisible identities is profound. To me, all of my identities are invisible, making experiences for me very different from those that are seeable.</description></item><item><title>Autism and Parenting</title><link>https://leehatcher.com/2020/07/autism-and-parenting/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://leehatcher.com/2020/07/autism-and-parenting/</guid><description>Effective Parenting for Children with Autism; Using Therapy to Create a Better Parent-Child
Relationship
Parents of children diagnosed with Autism Spectrum Disorder (ASD) face different challenges than those with neurotypical children; often they have little or no knowledge of ASD and therefore find it more difficult to ease into a natural parenting style with their child. Children with ASD often persistently struggle with social interaction, communication skills, and restrictive/repetitive behaviors, although the severity presents itself differently in every person (American Psychiatric Association, 2018).</description></item></channel></rss>